aa.org 2019-12-04

# Alcoholics Anonymous : Privacy Policy

Thank you for visiting the [www.AA.org](http://www.aa.org/) website and reviewing our Privacy Policy.  This policy explains how A.A.W.S. collects, uses, shares and protects personal information about you (meaning, information that can identify you personally or that can be used with other sources of information to identify you).  This policy applies to personal information you submit to us and other information we collect about you when you interact with our website or with A.A.W.S., as described below.  **PLEASE READ THE FOLLOWING TERMS CAREFULLY BEFORE USING THE WEBSITE OR PROVIDING INFORMATION TO A.A.W.S. THROUGH ANY OTHER MEANS**.

Certain apps and activities may be subject to additional or different privacy notices, which will be shared in connection with the relevant apps and activities.  Those notices are incorporated into this Privacy Policy by reference, but where they conflict with this policy, the supplemental notices control.

A.A.W.S. may modify this Privacy Policy at any time by posting an updated policy on this page.  If A.A.W.S. makes any material changes to this Privacy Policy, it will indicate the date the Privacy Policy was last revised at the top of this page.

**1\. Personal Information We Collect**  
__  
Information You Submit__  
You may submit certain personal information in connection with your use of our website, download and use of our apps, and participation in activities.  For example, if you purchase products on our website, make a contribution or register for one of our events, you may be asked to enter your name, email address, phone number, credit card information and address.  You may also submit personal information when you request information, customer service or other assistance, sign up to receive Daily Reflections or other newsletters or communications from us, submit your personal story, or otherwise communicate with us.

If you submit personal information on behalf of someone else, you must ensure and you certify that you have their authorization and consent to provide A.A.W.S. with their personal information.

We may receive personal information about you from our third party service providers, software or applications, who enable us to deliver our website, apps and online content to you, to process your orders and contributions, to manage events, and to provide other activities offered by A.A.W.S..  Our service providers are contractually bound to use your personal information only in accordance with our instructions and this Privacy Policy.  With your consent, the service providers may use of your personal information for other purposes as stated in that provider’s privacy policy.   
__  
Information Collected Automatically__  
In order to improve our website and to tailor our web services to your needs, A.A.W.S. may also automatically collect information about you when you use our website. The type of information collected includes information about your computer, mobile device, or other device that you use to access the website or other application(s), which may also include, for example, IP address, geolocation information, unique device identifiers, browser type, browser language, and other transactional information. We may also collect information about your use of our website and application(s), which may include, for example, a reading history of the pages you visit on our website.  
__  
Information Collected during our Conferences and Events__  
We may take photographs at our conferences and events. With your consent, we may publish these photographs on our website or our publications. You may withdraw your consent at any time.  
__  
Information from Local Groups, Intergroups/Central Offices & Area Committees__  
Local groups, intergroups/central offices and area committees are not part of A.A.W.S., and do not share information about you with A.A.W.S., unless you expressly consent to be listed in our internal directory of contacts for the groups, intergroups/central offices, or area committees, to be used for purposes of sending notifications and updates about the fellowship.

**2.** ******Use of Cookies**  
Like many websites, A.A.W.S. may use “cookies,” which are files stored on your device that help A.A.W.S. identify users and optimize their website experience.  Most browsers accept cookies automatically but allow you to disable them.  We recommend that you leave cookies enabled so we can offer you a better experience.  A.A.W.S. will not drop cookies or other tracking methods that are persistent and cannot be erased from a your device. Your IP address, searches, and other usage information are collected by Matomo analytics, but only to generate aggregate data to help us improve our website.

Our third-party providers may occasionally drop cookies on your device.  A.A.W.S. does not control these cookies, and these cookies fall outside the scope of this Privacy Policy.

**3\. Our Use of Information**  
We may use your information to provide and improve our website, apps, orders and activities, and to personalize your experience with the website, apps, orders and activities.  For example, we may use your personal information to: 

  * process and fulfill orders, contributions and other transactions;
  * organize and coordinate your participation in events, including travel arrangements and special accommodations that you request;
  * communicate with you about your account or information you have submitted, respond to your inquiries and requests for customer service or other assistance or information;
  * send Daily Reflections, newsletters and other communications that you have requested;
  * notify you about changes to our policies;
  * optimize or improve our website, apps, content, products, events, activities, communications and operations;
  * let you know about websites, apps, content, products, events, activities, promotions, features and functionality, that we think might be of interest to you; and 
  * detect, investigate, and prevent activities that may violate our terms or policies, applicable law or regulations, or the rights of any persons, organizations or entities.

**4\. Retention of Information**  
We delete your personal information as soon as we no longer need it in connection with the purpose for which it was submitted or collected, unless we are required by law to retain it for a longer time and we only retain it accordance with this Privacy Policy.

When you cancel an order, contribution or registration for an event, or stop participating in an event, or using a product, application, feature, activity or promotion, the service provider who processed your personal information may not automatically delete your personal information they have previously received, if information is still needed for the purpose for which it was collected.  We encourage you to read the privacy notices of these service providers, organizations and companies to make sure that you understand how they may use the personal information you provide to them.  You can engage directly with the service providers to if you have any concerns about the way they process your personal information.

**5.** ******Disclosure of Information**  
We will only disclose your Personal Information to other organizations, companies and individuals as described in this Privacy Policy.  
__  
Service Providers__  
A.A.W.S. occasionally engages third-party contractors and agents that provide services to A.A.W.S., such as credit card processing, order fulfillment, marketing, database hosting, web analytics, and providing customer service.  These entities may have access to Personal Information in order to perform their functions.  We do not authorize them to use the information we share with them for any other purpose.  
__  
Legally Compelled Disclosures__  
A.A.W.S. may disclose personal information to government authorities and other third parties when compelled to do so by law, including, without limitation, in response to court orders and subpoenas.  
__  
Emergency Situations__  
A.A.W.S. may disclose personal information if required to do or in the good-faith belief that such disclosure is necessary to (i) protect and defend its rights or property, the website or its members, and (ii) act under emergency circumstances to protect the personal safety of A.A.W.S. personnel, its members, or others.  
__  
Affiliated Entities__  
We may disclose personal information to our parent, subsidiary and other affiliated organizations, including the General Service Board, and A.A. Grapevine.  
__  
Change of Ownership or Organizational Structure__  
We may transfer personal information to another entity in connection with any change of ownership, change of organizational structure or similar transaction, such as, for example, a transfer to an entity with which we have merged, that we have acquired or that has acquired A.A.W.S.  Under such circumstances, A.A.W.S. will require the transferee to agree to follow the practices described in this Privacy Policy, as it may be amended from time to time.  
__  
Limited Publications__  
If you participate as a speaker at one of our events, your first name, last initial, and limited biographical information will be included in the event program, which are distributed to other event attendees and speakers, and copies retained in our archives.  If you submit a personal story, memoirs or correspondence and expressly consent to allow us to publish them, we may include them (in whole or in part), including such personal information as you have authorized us to publish, on our website and in digital and print publications, in accordance with the consent granted.  Copies the published stories will be retained in our archives. 

**6\. Security**  
We use appropriate technical and organizational measures to keep your personal information secure.

For example, payment card information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (“SSL”) technology and then encrypted into our payment gateway provider’s database only to be accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential.  Once a transaction is complete, your payment information will be deleted from our servers.

Though A.A.W.S. takes reasonable steps to protect the security and integrity of all personal information provided to A.A.W.S., due to the nature of the Internet, no transmission of data over the Internet is guaranteed to be completely secure.  It may be possible for third parties to intercept or access transmissions or private communications unlawfully, including when you contact A.A.W.S. by email or a “contact us” or similar feature on the website.  Accordingly, A.A.W.S. cannot guarantee that information, during transmission through the internet or while stored on its system or otherwise in its care, will be absolutely safe from intrusion by others, such as hackers.

**7.** ******Children**  
This website is not directed at children under the age of 13, and A.A.W.S. does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13 years of age.  If you are under 13 years of age you should not use this website, and under no circumstance should you provide personally identifiable information to A.A.W.S..

**8\. Referrals**  
A.A.W.S. may refer you to other websites, organizations or entities, in which case this Privacy Policy may not apply to information that you submit or make available to such websites, organizations and companies.  We encourage you to read the privacy notices of those websites, organizations and companies before submitting or making available any information to them.

**9\. Notice to Persons Outside of the United States**  
Please note that:

  * the personally identifiable information you provide to A.A.W.S. will be transferred to the United States for processing in accordance with this Privacy Policy, for which we will obtain your express consent, to the extent required by law;
  * you have the right to access your personal information upon request, to have it corrected as necessary, to have it deleted when you no longer want to use our website, download or use our app, participate in activities , or communication with us, or to have it transmitted to anyone you choose;
  * you also have the right to share your concerns about how we use and protect your information if you have any.

To exercise these rights, please contact our privacy office at [privacy@aa.org](mailto:privacy@aa.org).

If you are not satisfied with our response, you may file a complaint with your national data protection authority.

**10\. Questions?**  
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please use this website feedback form to contact us. 

_|Top |_
